<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Fire Folk</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/191837/Incarnate-The-Last-of-the-Lacers">Alex Tanner</author>
		<update version="0.3">
			<file name="fire-folk.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BloxBoss6/Incarnate-Last-of-the-Lacers/master/races/fire-folk.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

  <element name="Fire Folk" type="Race" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_RACE_FIRE_FOLK">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">"Fire is the element of power. The fire folk have desire and will, and the energy and drive to achieve what they want." - General Ichiro, The Division of the Elements</p>
      <p>The fire folk were seen as the warmongers of the world. While their personalities and convictions can be vibrant and passionate, this view of them is mostly unearned. Fire folk do have passion, but channel it into the pursuits shared by other races. Love, respect, community, family. Having a	zest for life is a hallmark of the fire folk, and it manifests in their daily lives.</p>

      <h4>BRASH AND BOLD</h4>
      <p>The fire folk empire once existed over a vast expanse, covering the volcanic islands of Wa in the east. That empire has since fallen, and even their largest city, Huo Cheng, was destroyed by a volcano. Most remaining fire folk can be found in Gongheguo City. Small populations also remain in tiny communities, hiding from larger nations.</p>
      <p class="indent">Fire folk usually stand between 5 and 6 feet tall. Their skin is typically fair compared to other human races. Hairstyles can say a	lot about a	ire folk as well. There are certain hairstyles and ceremonial top knots and ponytails that are reserved for royalty, and various hairstyles for other stations in life. Fire folk like to wear bold colors like reds and yellows.</p>

      <h4>FERVOR FOR LIFE</h4>
      <p>Of all the races, fire folk have the most zest. Fire folk have dozens of festivals, and find any excuse they can to throw a party. Festivals are held almost weekly, if not more so, with multiple reasons to celebrate life and love.</p>
      <p class="indent">The fire folk of Gongheguo City have the most advanced industry, and are the crafters of many different kinds of trinkets and treasures. Fire folk are also the biggest crafters of weapons and armor. In antiquity they were used for war or palace coups, but now they are only used for practice or ceremonial decoration.</p>

      <h4>VOLATILE THRONE, STEADY COMMUNITY</h4>
      <p>The fire folk typically live for less than a century. Of all the societies, fire folk could be considered the most changing. The rulers of the empire succeeded rapidly, and while the succession of the throne was typically handed down along familial lines, it was not uncommon for others to take over the throne for their own families. In recent times, the empire has fallen to the point where many families claim kinship with royal lines, but none have any true authority over other fire folk.</p>
      <p class="indent">Firelacing comes from the fire folk, and tradition dictates that the ability was originally learned from dragons. Dragons are seen as the original firelacers, and fire folk revere these powerful creatures in daily life. Firelacing masters spend years learning control over their abilities. Amateur firelacers might use their abilities indiscriminately, but only a	master will be able to exert true control over their fire, using it not only for its power, but for its soothing light.</p>

      <h4>FEARLESS AND RESOLUTE</h4>
      <p>While the fire folk can be seen as intimidating by other societies, the truth is that fire folk will be incredibly quick to trust someone and decide that they're a friend, and invite them along to festivals, or open their home to them.</p>
      <p class="indent"><b>Air Monks.</b> "Once you get to know them, the air monks can be really fun! They do their meditations, and that's great, but there's nothing more entertaining than getting an air monk to loosen up and tell you their stories."</p>
      <p class="indent"><b>Water Clan.</b> "I don't understand how the water clan can live in places that are so cold. And it's kind of strange that they don't have more contact with other people. Are they being secretive, or is it just because no one else goes there? They can be a little hard to trust."</p>
      <p class="indent"><b>Earth Kin.</b> "The earth kin are so structured, it can be a little infuriating. Even their festivals fall on such a strict schedule with specific rules on how to have fun. It's pretty rare to see an earth kin just cut loose and be unrestrained for once."</p>
      <p class="indent"><b>Obake.</b> "I'd love to meet an obake. People say they look like animals, and they love to play tricks. I wonder if that's true? If they do exist, they must keep to themselves, but I wouldn't hesitate to meet one!"</p>

      <h4>ON THE ROAD</h4>
      <p>Fire folk might be the people most suited for life on the road. Quick to make friends and sate others who might distrust them of their nature, a fire folk doesn't take another creature's reaction to them personally. They know of their own reputation, and find it's more prudent to simply lead by example and show why they would be great friends.</p>
      <p class="indent">Fire folk may become adventurers just for the love of travel, to make new friends, see strange lands, encounter weird new creatures, or test their might against dangerous spirits.</p>      

      <h4>FIRE FOLK NAMES</h4>
      <p>Fire folk names are granted at birth. Typically a fire folk will only have a single name, with distinguishing family names reserved only for high society. Fire folk names often low together, using softer consonants such as "z."</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Male Names:</span>Azata, Azumu, Daichi, Daizuke, Goro, Hachiro, Haruto, Haruzi, Hayato, Hideyoshi, Hinaza, Izuki, Jiro, Kaede, Katashi, Kazuo, Mazaru, Minoru, Noboru, Nori, Ozamu, Ryo, Shiro, Taro, Yazu, Yoshi, Zaburo, Zota<br/>
        <span class="feature">Female Names:</span>Aizo, Aimi, Azuko, Chizako, Chinatsu, Etsuko, Haruna, Hina, Hiroko, Izumi, Kazue, Kazuko, Kazumi, Mei, Midori, Mizuki, Natsuko, Rei, Satomi, Sayuri, Shizuka, Suzu, Suzume, Tomiko, Yoko, Yumi, Yuzuki<br/>
      </p>

      <h4>FIRE FOLK</h4>
      <p>Fire folk all have some things in common due to their shared heritage.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Charsima score increases by 2.<br />
        <span class="feature">Age.</span>. Fire folk reach adulthood at the age of 18 and typically live for less than a century.<br />
        <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Fire folk represent a widely diverse group of people. Some enjoy being lawful and following traditions; yet the spirit of irelacing leans towards chaos.<br />
        <span class="feature">Size.</span>Fire folk are typically between 5 and 6 feet tall. Your size is Medium<br />
        <span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br />
        <span class="feature">Positive Jing.</span>When you roll a 1 on a d20 for an attack roll, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.<br />
        <span class="feature">Bad Reputation.</span>You gain proficiency in the intimidation skill.<br />
        <span class="feature">Savage Elements.</span>When you score a crititcal hit with an elemental attack, you can roll one of the weapons damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.<br />
        <span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common and Kasai.<br />
        <span class="feature">Subrace.</span>While all fire folk share some qualities, a division in the use of firelacing caused a rift to appear, and eventually two separate groups emerged. Choose one of these subraces.<br />
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <setters>
      <set name="names" type="male">Azata, Azumu, Daichi, Daizuke, Goro, Hachiro, Haruto, Haruzi, Hayato, Hideyoshi, Hinaza, Izuki, Jiro, Kaede, Katashi, Kazuo, Mazaru, Minoru, Noboru, Nori, Ozamu, Ryo, Shiro, Taro, Yazu, Yoshi, Zaburo, Zota</set>
      <set name="names" type="female">Aizo, Aimi, Azuko, Chizako, Chinatsu, Etsuko, Haruna, Hina, Hiroko, Izumi, Kazue, Kazuko, Kazumi, Mei, Midori, Mizuki, Natsuko, Rei, Satomi, Sayuri, Shizuka, Suzu, Suzume, Tomiko, Yoko, Yumi, Yuzuki</set>
      <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
      <set name="height" modifier="2d10">4'8"</set>
      <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">110 lb.</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="charisma" value="2" />
      <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
      <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_POSITIVE_JING" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_BAD_REPUTATION" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SAVAGE_ELEMENTS" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_KASAI" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FIRE_FOLK_SUBRACE" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Positive Jing" type="Racial Trait" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_POSITIVE_JING">
    <description>
      <p>When you roll a 1 on the d20 for an attack roll, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you roll a 1 on the d20 for an attack roll, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <element name="Bad Reputation" type="Racial Trait" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_BAD_REPUTATION">
    <description>
      <p>You gain proficiency in the intimidation skill.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You gain proficiency in the intimidation skill.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Savage Elements" type="Racial Trait" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_RACIAL_SAVAGE_ELEMENTS">
    <description>
      <p>When you score a crititcal hit with an elemental attack, you can roll one of the weapons damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you score a crititcal hit with an elemental attack, you can roll one of the weapons damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <element name="Fire Folk Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FIRE_FOLK_SUBRACE">
    <description>
      <p>While all fire folk share some qualities, a division in the use of firelacing caused a rift to appear, and eventually two separate groups emerged. Choose one of these subraces.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Sub Race" name="Fire Folk Subrace" supports="Fire Folk" />
    </rules>
  </element>


  <element name="Dragon" type="Sub Race" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_SUB_RACE_DRAGON">
    <supports>Fire Folk</supports>
    <description>
      <p>As a	 dragon folk, you see dragons as the mightiest and most powerful of creatures. Many dragon folk communities spring up around actual dragons, which they revere and worship as the original firelacers. Dragon folk are rare, typically hiding their presence from other races in order to live in devotion to the true firelacing masters.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Dexterity score increases by 1.<br />
        <span class="feature">Dragon Worshipper.</span>You can cast the <i>cause fear</i> spell as a 1st-level spell once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the calm emotions spell as a	2nd-level spell once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.<br />
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DRAGON_WORSHIPPER" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Dragon Worshipper" type="Racial Trait" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DRAGON_WORSHIPPER">
    <description>
      <p>You can cast the <i>cause fear</i> spell as a 1st-level spell once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the calm emotions spell as a	2nd-level spell once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You can cast the <i>cause fear</i> spell as a 1st-level spell once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the calm emotions spell as a	2nd-level spell once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Qilin" type="Sub Race" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_SUB_RACE_QILIN">
    <supports>Fire Folk</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Qilin folk are by far the more prosperous and numerous. Qilin emerged as the more prominent of the two groups of fire folk, and many don’t believe that any dragon folk still exist. Qilin royalty advanced industry in an attempt to have a	forceful military power, but most qilin folk have distanced themselves from this, and lead simple and prosperous lives</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Strength score increases by 1.<br />
        <span class="feature">Qilin Weapon Training.</span>You have proficiency with the crossbow, halberd, longsword, shortsword, and spear.<br />
        <span class="feature">Qilin Armor Training.</span>You have proficiency with light and medium armor, and shields.<br />
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <stat name="strength" value="1" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_QILIN_WEAPON" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_QILIN_ARMOR" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Qilin Weapon Training" type="Racial Trait" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_QILIN_WEAPON">
    <description>
      <p>You have proficiency with the crossbow, halberd, longsword, shortsword, and spear.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You have proficiency with the crossbow, halberd, longsword, shortsword, and spear.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_LIGHT" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_HALBERD" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SPEAR" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Qilin Armor Training" type="Racial Trait" source="Incarnate: The Last of the Lacers" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_QILIN_ARMOR">
    <description>
      <p>You have proficiency with light and medium armor, and shields.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You have proficiency with light and medium armor, and shields.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  
</elements>